#### Serene Pon

## Head of Merchant Services at Ensogo Malaysia

(+60) 12 233 0335 | mw\_pon@yahoo.com | 31 years old | Puchong, Selangor, Malaysia

(+65) 8286 7275 (Singapore) | (+507) 6656 7320 (Panama) | Skype: serene.pon

# **Career Synopsis**

Serene is an experienced professional with 9 years in Telecommunication and E Commerce domain. She has experience in managing large teams of professionals (up to 20) and in managing high traffic operations in one of the largest telecommunication provider in Malaysia; Maxis Communication, with over 15,000 calls on a daily basis to maintain a high efficiency and low absenteeism work environment.

In addition to people management skills, she is also equipped with experience in E Commerce & Marketplace in setting up and restructuring businesses to provide support to clients and stake holders (both internal and external). Experienced in mapping Standard Operating Processes, Procedures and Process improvements to enhance and strengthen the operational flow.

# **Experience**

Feb 2015 – Jan 2016 (12 months)

#### **Head of Merchant Services**

### Ensogo Malaysia

- To setup operations for Malaysia marketplace.
- To restructure Merchant Services department.
- To manage Merchant Services team on daily operation tasks
- To setup the payout format for marketplace (Finance)
- To map and restructure the SOP (Standard Operating Procedures) for marketplace
- To improve on the Return policy, process & system.
- To improve on the merchants portal system for better accessibility
- To drive projects like On-boarding, Merchant Performance Review to enhance the merchant's efficiency & fulfillment rates.

Mar 2014 – Feb 2015 (12 months )

## **Head of Partner Support Center**

#### Lazada Malaysia

- To setup Partner Support Center (PSC) for MY Marketplace
- To manage the PSC team on daily task as well as projects
- To draw out the SOPP for PSC
- To assist on process improvement plan for Marketplace Operations
- To build a stronger relationship with merchants from Marketplace
- To do service recovery for PSC

Oct 2010 - Mar 2014 (3 years 5 months)

# **Customer Operation Executive**Maxis Bhd

Manage team and operation floor (Floor Captain) in contact center, servicing customer in their enquires, request and complaint for Maxis postpaid subscribers, Team Leader to drive team to achieve monthly goals as well as drive team to career progression.

Converted from a 3rd party contract to a permanent position as a team leader after servicing Maxis for 1year 6months (acting TL position for 5mths), received written compliment from Head of Customer Operation, recognition from Jobsteert.com as outstanding performance.

Mar 2009 - Sep 2010 (1 year 6 months)

### **Customer Care Consultant**

#### JobStreet.com

Based in Maxis Bhd to support Maxis Contact Center in handling inbound calls and servicing Maxis postpaid subscribers on their enquires, requests as well as complaints.

Jul 2007 - Feb 2009 (1 year 7 months)

# **Graphic Designer**

Red Antz Group Sdn Bhd

Generate ideas, prepare presentation materials to final artworks and support event team in executing the end product in events.

#### **Education**

2007

## **Multimedia University**

Bachelor's Degree in Art/Design/Creative Multimedia | Malaysia

Major Interface Design
Grade Pass/Non-gradable

#### **Skills**

Intermediate Basic  ${\bf Adobe\ Illustrator,\ Adobe\ PhotoShop,\ 3D\ Studio\ Max}$ 

Adobe In-Design, Photography, AutoCad

# Languages

Proficiency level: 0 - Poor, 10 - Excellent

Language	Spoken	Written	Relevant Certificates
English	9	7	-
Bahasa Malaysia	6	5	-
Mandarin	3	0	-
Cantonese	6	0	-

## **About Me**

Gender Female
Nationality Malaysian
Telephone Number (+60) 12-233 0335

Alternative Numbers (+65) 8286 7275 (Singapore) | (+507) 6656 7320 (Panama)

Skype ID serene.por

LinkedIn https://my.linkedin.com/pub/serene-pon/85/5b7/550

Address No 37, Jalan Putra Perdana 6/7, Taman Putra Perdana, 47100 Puchong, Selangor.